lalpathlabs.com 2015-03-16

# Dr Lal PathLabs - Diagnostic Center, Blood test & Health CheckUps

### Privacy Policy

This privacy policy ("Privacy Policy") sets forth our commitment to respecting your online privacy and recognize your need for appropriate protection and management of any Personal Information (as defined below) you share with us. The Privacy Policy applies to our Services available under the domain www.lalpathlabs.com (herein after referred to as the "Website"). By visiting the Website you agree to be bound by the terms and conditions of this Privacy Policy. 

IF YOU DO NOT AGREE PLEASE DO NOT USE OR ACCESS THE WEBSITE.  
The words "you" or "your" or "User" "Customer" as used herein, refer to all individuals and/or entities accessing or using the Website for any reason. The words "we" or "us" or "our" or the "Company" as used herein, refer to the Dr Lal PathLabs Pvt. Ltd. and/or or any permitted assignees. 

This Privacy Policy describes the information, as part of the normal operation of our Services; we collect from you and what may happen to that information. Although this policy may seem long, we have prepared a detailed policy because we believe you should know as much as possible about the Website, Services and our practices so that you can make informed decisions.

By accepting the Privacy Policy and the Terms of Use, which prescribes terms and conditions for use of Website or availing Services, you expressly consent to our use and disclosure of your personal information in accordance with this Privacy Policy. This Privacy Policy is incorporated into and subject to the terms of the Terms of Use and the terms not defined here, have there meanings ascribed to in the Terms of Use. This Privacy Policy and Terms of Use are effective upon your visit of Website. We encourage you read the terms of the Privacy Policy and the Terms of Use in their entirety before you use the Website.

1\. Your Privacy - Our Commitment

We are extremely proud of our commitment to protect your privacy. We value your trust in us. We will work hard to earn your confidence so that you can enthusiastically use our services and recommend us to friends and family. Please read the following policy to understand how your Personal Information will be treated as you make full use of our Website. 

For the purposes of this Privacy Policy, the term "Personal Information" shall mean any information that may be used to identify you including, but not limited to, (i) first and last name with salutation, a home or other physical address and an email address or other contact information, whether at work or at home, (ii) age and gender (iii) correspondence address (iv) should you suffer from any physical/mental infirmities all the information in relation thereto (the amount of information you choose to keep confidential is entirely up to your discretion; you may enter as much or as little information as you choose, except for the information which is mandatorily required).The information essentially required for conducting the test may be gathered at the time when the patient gets registered at any authorized centre of the company for which the patients confidentially accesses their reports (password protected) online on the official website of the company. 

2\. Information we collect

When you use our Website, we collect and store your Personal Information. Our primary goal in doing so is to provide a safe, efficient and customized experience to our Users. This allows us to provide services and features that most likely meet your needs, and to customize our Website to make your experience safer and easier. Importantly, we only collect Personal Information about you that we consider necessary for achieving this purpose.

In general, you can browse the Website without telling us who you are or revealing any personal information about yourself. To fully use our Website, you will need to register using our online registration form, where you may be required to provide us with your contact and identity information and other Personal Information as indicated on the forms throughout the Website and complete the Registration Process. Once you give us your Personal Information, and initiate Registration Process, you are not anonymous to us. Where possible, we indicate which fields are mandatorily required and which fields are optional. You always have the option to not provide information by choosing not to use a particular service or feature on the Website, unless we require it so. 

We may automatically track certain information about you based upon your behavior on our Website. You agree that we may use such information to do internal research on our Users' demographics and medical history to better understand, protect and serve our Users. This information is compiled and analyzed on an aggregated basis. This information may include, but not limited to, the URL that you just came from (whether this URL is on our site or not), which URL you next go to (whether this URL is on our Website or not), your computer browser information, and your Internet Protocol ("IP") address.

We use data collection devices such as "cookies" on certain pages of the Website to help analyze our web page flow, measure promotional effectiveness, and promote trust and safety. "Cookies" are small files placed on your hard drive that assist us in providing our services. We offer certain features that are only available through the use of a "cookie". We also use cookies to allow you to enter your password less frequently during a session. Cookies can also help us provide information that is targeted to your interests. Most cookies are "session cookies," meaning that they are automatically deleted from your hard drive at the end of a session. You are always free to decline our cookies if your browser permits, although in that case you may not be able to use certain features on the Website and you may be required to reenter your password more frequently during a session.

You agree, if you send us personal correspondence in any electronic form, such as emails,, letters,etc or if other users or third parties send us correspondence about your activities or postings on the Website, we may collect and/or store such information.

You agree that we may collect IP address from all visitors to the Website, like most websites. An IP address is a number that is automatically assigned to your computer when you use the Internet. We use IP addresses to help diagnose problems with our server, administer our Website, analyze trends, track users' movement, gather broad demographic information for aggregate use in order for us to improve the Website, and deliver customized, personalized content.

3\. Use of your Personal Information

You agree that we may use your Personal Information to facilitate the services you request. You agree that we may use your Personal Information and other information we obtain on the Website or at the time of Patient registration to: enable detailed examination of the medical tests conducted, inform you about online and offline offers, products, services, password retrieval and updates; customize your experience; enforce Terms of Use; and as otherwise described to you at the time of collection. 

You agree that we may use Personal Information about you to improve our marketing and promotional efforts, to analyze site usage, improve the Website's content and service offerings, and customize the Website's content, layout, and services. These uses improve the Website and better tailor it to meet your needs, so as to provide you with an efficient, safe and customized experience while using the Website.

You agree that we may use your Personal Information to contact you and deliver information to you that, in some cases, are targeted to your interests, such as targeted banner advertisements, administrative notices, services offerings, and communications relevant to your use of the Website. By accepting the Terms of Use and Privacy Policy, you expressly agree to receive this information. If you do not wish to receive these communications, we encourage you to unsubscribe / opt out of the receipt of certain communications in your profile. You may make changes to your profile at any time. 

4\. Disclosure of your Personal Information

You agree and confirm that we do not rent, sell, or share Personal Information about you with other people (save with your consent) or non-affiliated companies except to provide products or Services under Terms of Use or this Privacy Policy, or under the following circumstances:

  1. to provide the Personal Information to physicians and other authorized health care professionals who need to access your laboratory report for your proper diagnosis;
  2. to insurance companies, hospitals, physicians or third parties with our billing department for payment purpose;
  3. to support our health care operations, such as performing quality checks on your testing, for teaching purposes, or for developing normal reference ranges for the tests we perform;
  4. to respond to summons, court orders, or legal process, or to establish or exercise our legal rights or defend against legal claims;
  5. to health department or any other Government body as and when required by them for collecting or processing health information of the state/country;
  6. from time to time, to reveal general statistical information about our Website and visitors, such as number of visitors, number and type of services purchased, etc;
  7. to transfer Personal Information about you to trusted partners, may or may not for gain, to promote certain products/services for commercial purposes, without any prior notice to you.

Further, you agree that we may share your Personal Information with the following categories of activities with from time-to-time: 

  1. Advertisements
    1. When you enter Personal Information on any form of an advertiser, such information is simultaneously collected by Website and the advertiser. The Personal Information is used by Website in accordance with the terms of this Privacy Policy and is used by the advertiser as per the advertiser's prevalent privacy policies. Because we do not control the privacy practices of these advertisers, you should evaluate their practices before deciding to provide the said information. 
    2. Website may also aggregate (gather up data across all accounts) Personal Information and disclose such information in a non-personally identifiable manner to advertisers and other third parties for other marketing and promotional purposes.
  2. Other Corporate Entities.
    1. The Company shares much of the data, including Personal Information about you, with its parent, affiliates, subsidiaries, and joint ventures that are committed to serving your online needs and related services, throughout the world. To the extent that these entities have access to your Personal Information, they will treat it at least as protectively as they treat information they obtain from their other users. The Company's parent, affiliates, subsidiaries, and joint ventures follow privacy practices no less protective of all users than our practices described in this document, to the extent allowed by applicable law. The Company, its parent, affiliates, subsidiaries, its joint ventures, or any combination of such, will share some or all of your Personal Information with another business entity should we plan to, merge with, or be acquired by that business entity. 
  3. Posting to public areas of the website 
    1. Please remember that if you post any of your Personal Information in public areas of the Website such as in online forums or chat rooms, or in the Website's searchable database, such information may be collected and used by others over whom we have no control. We are not responsible for the use made by third parties of information you post or otherwise make available in public areas of Website.

5\. Access or change your Personal Information

You may review, correct, update or change your account information at any time.  
To protect your privacy and security, we will verify your identity before granting access or making changes to your Personal Information. If you have registered your profile on the Website, your ID and Password are required in order to access your Account. 

6\. Other websites

Our Website may contain links to other websites. Please note that when you click on one of these links, you are entering another website over which the Website has no control and will bear no responsibility. Often these websites require you to enter your Personal Information. We encourage you to read the privacy statements on all such websites as their policies may differ from ours. You agree that we shall not be liable for any breach of your privacy of Personal Information or loss incurred by your use of these websites.

7\. Changes to this Privacy Policy

We reserve the right to update, change or modify this Privacy Policy at any time. The amendment to this Privacy Policy shall come to effect from the time of such update, change or modification and the same will be published on this Website.

8\. Disclaimer

The Company does not access, store or keep credit card data. All credit card transactions happen using Secure Server Software (SSL) for 128 bit encryption through third party gateways and the Company plays no role in the transaction, except for directing the customers to gateways or relevant webpage. Accordingly, the Company shall not be responsible or liable for any loss or damage due to any disclosure whatsoever of Personal Information.

The Company shall not be liable for any loss or damage sustained by reason of any disclosure (inadvertent or otherwise) of any Personal Information concerning the User's account and / or information relating to or regarding online transactions using credit cards / debit cards /cash cards and / or their verification process and particulars nor for any error, omission or inaccuracy with respect to any information so disclosed and used.

9\. Governing law and Dispute Resolution

This Privacy Policy and Terms of Use shall be governed by and constructed in accordance with the laws of India only without reference to conflict of laws principles and disputes arising in relation hereto and shall be subject to the exclusive jurisdiction of the competent courts of New Delhi, India. 

10\. Assignability

The Company may assign any of its responsibilities/obligations to any other person without notice to the User, at its sole discretion. However, you shall not assign, sub-licence or otherwise transfer any of your rights under this Privacy Policy to any other party, unless a written consent is taken from the Company.

11\. Contacting the Website

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, the privacy practices of this Website, or if you want to exercise any of the rights that you are given under this Privacy Policy, you can contact us at shakti.shrivastava@lalpathlabs.com
